S. Guy Endore papers, 1925-1970
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Manuscripts by Guy Endore
  - A Walk in Alabama. Los Angeles and n.p., April 6, 1965 and undated (Box 47)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. Los Angeles., (13pp.) (Box 47)
      With a note that this was a talk given to the School of Library Service, UCLA.
  - A World I Never Made. n.p., undated; (27 leaves, typescript and holograph) (Box 47)
    Drafts and related material.
  - “War Yes, Sex No”., 1963 (Box 23)
    - In Push Pin Graphic (no.43)., 1963 (Box 23)
      From a talk given before the graduating class of the School of Library Service, UCLA, May 25, 1962.
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. n.p., undated; (19pp.) (Box 59)
    - War Yes, Sex No. Los Angeles., undated; (28pp., typescript carbon) (Box 59)
  - The Werewolf of Paris. Los Angeles., 1933 (Boxes 28, 68)
    - Galleys., 1933; (80 leaves) (Box 28)
    - Ephemera Curse of the Werewolf (film adaptation)., (28 items) (Box 68)
  - Zorina. n.p., undated (Box 47)
  - Zorina. n.p., undated; (7pp., typescript carbon, in grey cover) (Box 47)
    With 5 leaves of notes laid in.
    Registered with the Screen Writers Guild.
  - Zorina. n.p., undated; (7pp. Typescript with a carbon copy. Both in grey covers) (Box 47)
- [Manuscripts by Guy Endore and Others]
  - Between Heaven and Hell. (Original story) by Guy Endore and Alexander Benzion. n.p., undated; (72 leaves Typescript. With orange cover) (Box 39)
  - Clasp Hands Around the World. By Marcel Frym and Guy Endore. n.p., undated (Box 40)
    - Typescript., undated; (8 leaves) (Box 40)
    - Typescript., 1946(?); (13 leaves) (Box 40)
    - Typescript carbon., undated; (19 leaves) (Box 40)
    - Typescript., 1946; (15 leaves) (Box 40)
      With letter of transmittal from Marcel Frym, January 5, 1946.
  - Fascination. Original story by Alexander Benzion. Treatment by Guy Endore., (18 leaves, typescript carbon with grey cover) (Box 41)
  - Honorable Assassins. A screen story about the Japanese enemy by Guy Endore and Herbert Kline. Hollywood., 1942(?); (78pp., mimeograph with corrections. With tan cover) (Box 43)
    Alternate titles: Hirohito's Children and Son of a Samurai.
    - Mimeograph with corrections., 1942(?); (78pp., with tan cover) (Box 43)
    - Mimeograph., 1942(?); (78pp., with orange covers) (Box 43)
      2 copies.
  - Methinks the Lady. Screenplay by Harry Kleiner and Guy Endore. New York: Duell, Sloan & Pearce., 1945 (Boxes 9, 10, 45, 67)
    - Typescript, original., (In black cloth slipcase) (Box 9)
    - Typescript carbon., (In blue binder) (Box 9)
    - Typescript memo to printer re corrections (Box 9)
    - Mimeographed screen version., June 12, 1945; (In blue binder) (Box 9)
    - Mimeographed synopsis., November 18, 1945 (Box 9)
    - Outline for screen version., January 23, 1946; (Typescript carbon) (Box 9)
    - First draft of screen version., February 19, 1946; (Typescript carbon, in blue binder) (Box 9)
    - Second draft of screen version., April 2, 1946; (Typescript carbon, in blue ringer binder) (Box 9)
    - Typescript and holograph pages in preparation of book. (Box 10)
      Also: Newspaper clipping re screenplay prospects.
    - Copy of the book (Box 10)
    - Typescript carbon. Los Angeles., 1945; (221pp., with black cover) (Box 45)
      With Endore's memo re screen treatment, July 19, 1945.
      For Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer.
    - Treatment. Culver City., June 12, 1945; (96pp., typescript carbon with blue cover) (Box 45)
      With 2 clippings on divorce and polygamy.
    - Memos. Beverly Hills., 1945-1946; (4 items) (Box 45)
      Memos from Craig Rice, Guy Endore, Otto Preminger, and Lou Shore regarding production of Methinks the Lady.
    - Typescript carbon. n.p., undated; (265pp., with blue cover) (Box 45)
      Handled by Nat Goldstone Agency.
    - First draft continuity. Los Angeles., July 5, 1946; (134pp.) (Box 45)
      For Twentieth Century-Fox Film Corporation.
    - Galleys (Box 45)
    - Ephemera., (77 items) (Box 67)
  - The Military and the Struggle for Peace. By Mary Clarke and Guy Endore. n.p., June 19, 1965; (7 leaves, mimeograph with holograph corrections) (Box 45)
  - Project for a Red Cross scenario. Irmgard von Cube and Guy Endore. n.p., undated; (3 leaves Mimeograph) (Box 46)
  - Reluctant her. by Jessica Benson and Guy Endore. Los Angeles., undated; (65pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
    Registered with the Screen Writers Guild, no.10799. Hilary Lynn's name has been crossed out, and replaced with Jessica Benson on the title page.
  - We Leave Memory. By Milton Merlin and Guy Endore. n.p., January 17, 1938; (23pp., mimeograph with blue cover) (Box 47)
    Screen treatment concerning Emperor Norton.
  - The Fall of Rome. A screenplay by Guy Endore and William Copeland. Los Angeles and n.p., undated (Boxes 17, 18, 21, 41)
    - Typescript carbon., (300 leaves, in a blue manila folder) (Box 18)
    - Dahn, Felix. Ein Kampf um Rom. Historischer Roman. München, Deutsches Verlagshaus Bong., undated; It was from this novel that Guy Endore and William Copeland wrote their screenplay, The Fall of Rome. (Box 17)
    - Story treatment for the screenplay. Los Angeles., undated; (16 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections in red ink) (Box 21)
    - Typescript with copious holograph corrections and additions. Los Angeles., undated; (136 leaves); Early draft of a screenplay adapted from Ein Kampf un Rom. (Box 21)
    - Typescript carbon with copious notes by Endore in red ink. Los Angeles., undated; (82 leaves, on white paper) (Box 21)
    - Typescript, mostly carbon. Los Angeles., undated; (300 leaves, on yellow paper) (Box 21)
    - First draft screenplay. Los Angeles., undated; (300 leaves, typescript carbon. In blue wrappers on white paper) (Box 21)
    - Screenplay. n.p., undated; (pp.125-299, tncomplete typescript carbon) (Box 41)
    - Holograph, with doodles by Guy Endore. n.p., undated; (9 leaves) (Box 41)
  - I Walk in Liberty by Guy Endore, William Copeland, and De Witt Bodeen. n.p., 1940; (124 leaves, typescript in black cover) (Box 29)
  - House of Treason. By Guy Endore and William Copeland. n.p., undated (Box 43)
    - Typescript carbon., (125pp.) (Box 43)
    - Typescript with corrections by Guy Endore., (102 leaves, with tan cover) (Box 43)
- [Story Ideas, Untitled Manuscripts, etc.]
  - re Jews and German. n.p., undated; (12 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 44)
  - re peace movement. n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript) (Box 46)
  - Story idea re psychoanalysis. n.p., undated; (10 leaves, typescript, Typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - Racing story. Los Angeles., 1964; (17pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
    Brief suggestion for theme, mood and characters of racing story (From Alfred Neubauer's book of reminiscences: Men, Women and Motors).
    With letter of transmittal from Endore to Bob, Los Angeles, June 11, 1964.
  - re Shakers. n.p., April 24, 1940; (7pp., typescript carbon) (Box 46)
  - Story ideas, fragments. n.p., undated; (100 leaves, holograph, typescript) (Box 48)
  - Script pages. n.p., October 16, 1947; (3 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 48)
  - Untitled lecture. n.p., undated; (9 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 48)
    Also, 3 variant copies.
  - A play in which Jews are discussed; probably never produced. n.p., undated; (37 leaves, mimeographed) (Box 27)
  - Untitled screenplay. North Hollywood., April 3, 1943; (160pp., mimeograph) (Box 48)
    Signed by Guy Endore on title page. Republic Studios, production no.1171, associate producer: Albert H. Cohen.
  - Untitled screenplay. n.p., 1949; (pp.2-156, 30-67, typescript carbon) (Box 48)
  - Untitled story. New York., undated; (8 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 48)
    Setting of the story is Central Africa.
  - Untitled story (2 copies). n.p., undated; (29pp., typescript carbon) (Box 48)
    With bibliography from Hatha Yoga.
- [Manuscripts Edited by Guy Endore]
  - Ben-Hur: a Tale of Christ by Lewis Wallace, edited by Guy Endore. Published as paperback abridged version by New York: Dell., 1959 (Box 11)
    - Book with manuscript., (Typescript carbon) (Box 11)
      Also: 2 typescripts with extensive holograph corrections.
    - Chapters 9-17., (Typescript with holograph corrections, iregular pagination. 1 reel, positive) (Box 11)
    - Carbon copy of Ben-Hur for Henry Simon, Simon & Schuster. Rockefeller Center, New York., (Typescript carbon with a few corrections by Endore in red ink, 26, 422 leaves) (Box 18)
    - Ephemera., (28 items) (Box 67)
- Manuscripts by Others
  - Abbe J.A. Dubois and Endore peace message. n.p., undated (Box 39)
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. n.p., undated; (3 leaves) (Box 39)
      With another version (5 leaves, typescript carbon).
    - Typescript with holograph corrections. n.p., undated; (11 leaves) (Box 39)
      With another version (11 leaves, typescript carbon)
  - West, Samuel B. The Scimitar (Screenplay). Los Angeles., May 24, 1961; (122 leaves, typescript carbon, in a tan folder) (Box 20)
  - West, Samuel B. The Sword of Baristan (Screenplay). Los Angeles., July 11, 1961; (156 leaves, mimeographed, in a blue manila folder) (Box 20)
  - West, Samuel B. Captain Sindbad (Screenplay). Los Angeles., 1961 (Boxes 20, 40, 67)
    - Mimeograph., August 5, 1961; (141 leaves, in a green manila folder) (Box 20)
    - Mimeograph (marked copy 111). Hollywood., August 5, 1961; (141pp., with a green cover) (Box 40)
    - Mimeograph (in German, copy no.5). Drehbuch von Samuel B. West. Hollywood., January 15, 1952; (137pp.) (Box 40)
    - Ephemera., (1 item) (Box 67)
  - 3 drafts of a screenplay. (Box 20)
    With a folder containing 3 letters (carbons) from Guy Endore to Frank, giving advice on scripts.
    Also: Typewritten notes by Endore re Captain Sindbad (2 items).
    All marked Property of: King Bros. Productions, Inc.
  - Höllering, Franz. Ein Kampf um Rom. Treatment für zwei Filme nach dem gleichnamigen Roman von Felix Dahn, von Franz HoPHllering und Stefan Graf. Alle Recte bei Excelsior Ag. Chur Filmvertriebs-Gesellschaft, MasanserStrasse 32, Chur/Schweiz., (83, 61 leaves, mimeographed. In maroon wrappers) (Box 21)
  - Cohn, Art. Tomorrow is Another Day (Copy 116). Los Angeles., December 28, 1950; (119pp.) (Box 48)
    Part 1, final.
    For Warner Brothers Pictures, Incorporated.
  - Tiempo, Cesar. Our Daily Bread. n.p., 1948; (63pp., typescript carbon) (Box 48)
    Translated by Donald E. Walsh with letter of transmittal from Walsh to Endore, February 23, 1948.
  - Tiempo, Cesar. El regreso de Lazaro. Buenos Aires., 1947; (17pp., typescript carbon) (Box 48)
    Cinedrama de: Cesar Tiempo; Basado en un relato de: Guy Endore. With 4 clippings re Cesar Tiempo and Guy Endore, and a memo from Robert Shaw, Screen Writers Guild, to Philip and Janet Stevenson, August 25, 1947.
  - Possessed. A screen story by Janet Stevenson, Ralph Steiner, and Benno Schneider (Box 46)
    Based on a short story by Guy Endore. Also known as: Dead Man's Lust
    - Typescript carbon., (51pp.) (Box 46)
    - Typescript carbon. Hollywood., July 1934; (45pp., with partial blue cover) (Box 46)
- Manuscript Material Concerning Novels by Guy Endore
  - Material for a proposed novel about Honore de Balzac (Box 49)
    - Endore's notes re Nadeau, Maurice (Balzac). n.p., undated; (4 leaves, typescript carbon) (Box 49)
    - Notes re Balzac. n.p., undated; (300 leaves Holograph, typescript) (Box 49)
- House Un-American Activities Committee and the Hollywood Blacklist
  - Abolish the House Committee on Un-American Activities. n.p., undated; (10pp., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 66)
    With another copy (14pp., typescript carbon).
  - Committee of 23. Drafts of statements, press releases. n.p., undated; (4 items) (Box 66)
  - Guy Endore's account of an F.B.I. visit. Los Angeles., December 3, 1959; (4pp. Typescript) (Box 66)
  - Guy Endore's statements to the Screen Writers' Guild, and comments on the House Un-American Activities Commission testimony mentioning him. n.p., undated; (2 items) (Box 66)
    With this: p.8 of another unidentified statement.
  - Affidavit of Guy Endore. Los Angeles., February 15, 1958; (7pp., typescript carbon) (Box 66)
    With letter of transmittal from Frank Ferguson, July 28, 1964.
  - Guy Endore. Open letter re blacklisting. n.p., undated; (1p., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 66)
  - Guy Endore. “To whom it doesn't in the least concern....” Los Angeles., August 5, 1952; (1p) (Box 66)
  - Publications related to the blacklist., (36 items) (Box 66)
    Includes:
    U.S. Court of Appeals, no.13480, Oleta O'Connor Yates, et al., vs. the United States of America, Brief
    Michael Wilson, et al., vs. Loew's International, October 1957, no.37 (U.S. Supreme Court), Brief for Petitioners
  - Notes on Rosenberg case., (8 items) (Box 66)
    Includes correspondence with Committee To Serve Justice In The Rosenberg Case, and copy of A letter to I.F. Stone about the Rosenberg case. v.p., 1953.
  - re Guy Endore's candicacy for executive board of the Screen Writers' Guild., (2 items) (Box 66)
  - Correspondence and notes regarding Wilson vs. Loew. v.p., 1957-1958; (25 items) (Box 66)
    Includes Endore's notes regarding the loyalty oath, correspondence with committee members (Committee of 23), and summary of the case.
  - Endore's notes re House Un-American Activities Commission (HUAC) and the blacklist. n.p., undated; (13 leaves, typescript, holograph) (Box 66)
  - Correspondence re the blacklist, primarily from Endore to various persons (Box 66)
    - Arens, Richard C., House Un-American Activities Committee. Los Angeles., June 28, 1958; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Authors Guild, New York. v.p., 1952-1953; (2 items, with enclosure) (Box 66)
    - Brackett, Charles. Hollywood., August 5, 1954; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Burns, Hugh M. v.p., 1954; (5 items) (Box 66)
      Letters to the California Legislative Committee on Un-American Activities with notes and drafts of letter.
    - Chase, Borden. n.p., undated; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Cohn, Harry. Los Angeles., December 6, 1955; (1 item. Endore's typescript draft with corrections) (Box 66)
    - Cohn, Sidney. Los Angeles., October 19, 1956; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Doyle, Clyde. Los Angeles., April 3, 1953; (2 items) (Box 66)
      Includes carbon copy.
    - The Eagle. (Dear Mrs. Bass). n.p., undated; (5pp., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 66)
      A draft (?) but signed by Endore on p.5.
    - Hollywood Reporter. Los Angeles., August 26, 1952; (1 item. With clipping attached) (Box 66)
    - Hollywood Ten. Open letter. n.p., undated; (6pp.) (Box 66)
      “H'wd 10, (November 11)”
    - Kahane, Ben. Los Angeles., 1955-56; (3 items (Box 66)
    - Knaupf, David M. v.p., 1962; (4 items) (Box 66)
    - Los Angeles Times., 1953-1954; (6 items) (Box 66)
      Includes clipping, draft and another copy of Endore's letter to the Times.
    - McWilliams, Carey. v.p., 1957; (4 items) (Box 66)
      Includes Endore's drafts.
    - Margolis, Ben. Los Angeles., 1952-1956; (9 items) (Box 66)
      Includes drafts of letters, copy of retainer agreement, questionnaire regarding the 1952 Hollywood Blacklist case and Endore's responses
    - New York Times., 1954; (5 items) (Box 66)
      Includes Endore's letter (March 13, 1954), another copy, and drafts of statements intended for the New York Times(?).
    - Poe, Elizabeth. n.p., 1954-1955; (4 items) (Box 66)
    - Schary, Dore. n.p., 1952; (1 item) (Box 66)
      Endore's draft letter to Schary with clipping.
    - Screen Writers' Guild Los Angeles., 1954; (3 items) (Box 66)
    - Stark, Ray. n.p., 1957; (2 items) (Box 66)
    - Stillman, David. n.p., 1958; (12 items) (Box 66)
    - Teachers Defense Committee. n.p., 1954; (7 items) (Box 66)
    - Trumbo, Dalton., 1956-1957; (2 items) (Box 66)
      Trumbo's letter of December 30, 1956 to Endore regarding a previous discussion about the blacklist. With Endore's reply.
    - U.S. Department of State., 1957; (2 items) (Box 66)
    - Uris, Micky and Dorothy., 1957; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Walter, Francis E., 1958; (1 item) (Box 66)
    - Welch, Joseph., 1957; (2 items) (Box 66)
    - Wheeler, Bill., 1958; (1 item) (Box 66)
- [Misacellaneous] Ephemera Files
  - Casanova., (82 items) (Box 67)
  - re Guy Endore., (17 items) (Box 67)
  - Los Angeles murders., (1 item) (Box 67)
  - Mad love., (13 items) (Box 67)
  - The man from limbo., (7 items) (Box 67)
  - The man that was Shakespeare., (1 item) (Box 67)
  - Mark of the vampire., (15 items) (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous., (17 items) (Box 68)
  - Murder by the dozen (What Can a Man Want)., (1 item) (Box 68)
  - Sleepy Lagoon., (16 items) (Box 68)
    - Editorial: Youthful gang secrets exposed: young hoodlums smoke 'reefers,' tattoo girls and plot robberies; in Los Angeles Times, 1944 July 16 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Mexicans have found American champions; in Globe and Mail, 1944 September 11; McAree, John Verner (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Sleepy Lagoon: name of song has become national disgrace, novelist says, 1944; Endore, S. Guy, 1901-1970 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      Newspaper (not indicated in clipping) reprint of Guy Endore's speech given on the Al Jarvis radio show, KFWB.
    - Attorneys demand release of Sleepy Lagoon youths, 1944 October (Box 68, Folder 2)
      With the reversal of the convictions in the Appellate Court, the defendants' attorneys press for their clients immediate release.
    - Conviction of 12 reversed in Sleepy Lagoon murder: evidence too weak for guilty verdict, Appeal Court says, 1944 October (Box 68, Folder 2)
      Newspaper clipping; no indication of date or from which newspaper.
  - Song of Russia., (5 items) (Box 68)
  - The Sword of God., (4 items) (Box 68)
  - Translations by Guy Endore., (2 items) (Box 68)
  - Vampires of Prague., (4 items) (Box 68)
  - Scrapbook., 1929-1934; (1 item) (Box (flat box) 69*)
    Inscribed To Henrietta P. Endore from S. Guy Endore on front pastedown.
    Includes reviews of the following books by Guy Endore, as well as book reviews by him:
    -New American Caravan.
    -Casanova.
    -The man from Limbo.
    -Sword of God: Jeanne d'Arc.
    -Werewolf of Paris.
    -Babouk.
- Material re the Kennedy Assassination and the Warren Commission Report
  - Manuscript material by Guy Endore regarding the Warren Commission Report. n.p., undated; (7 leaves, typescript with holograph corrections and 7pp., mimeograph) (Box 70)
    With this: transcript of broadcast by Jim Garrison, November 1967, with cover letter.
  - Ephemera collected by Guy Endore re the Kennedy assassination and the Warren Commission Report (Boxes 70-71)
    - Book Week. New York., 2 items: (Box 70)
      (vol.3 no.46), July 24, 1966
      (vol.3 no.51), August 28, 1966
    - Commentary. New York., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.44 no.1), July 1967
    - Critical Reactions to the Warren Report. New York: Marzani & Munsell., 1964; (65pp., 1 item) (Box 70)
    - Daily Variety. Hollywood., 3 items: (Box 70)
      (vol.116 no.16), June 27, 1967
      (vol.136 no.17), June 28, 1967
      (vol.136 no.18), June 29, 1967
    - Fact. New York., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.3 no.6), November-December 1966
    - Frontier. Los Angeles., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.17, no.12), October 1966
    - Historia. Milan., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.37 no.216), November 1964
    - I.F. Stone's Weekly. Washington, D.C., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.15 no.2), January 16, 1967
    - Ladies' Home Journal. Philadelphia., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.84 no.3), March 1967
    - Liberation. New York., 1 item: (Box 70)
      (vol.11 no.7), October 1966
    - LIFE. New York., 3 items: (Box 70)
      (vol.59 no.9), August 27, 1965
      (vol.61 no.22), November 25, 1966
      (vol.63 no.21), November 24, 1967
    - Look. New York., 4 items: (Box 70)
      (vol.28 no.23), November 17, 1964
      (vol.30 no.14), July 12, 1966
      (vol.31 no.2), January 24, 1967
      (vol.31 no.3), February 7, 1967
    - Look. New York., 4 items: (Box 70)
      (vol.31 no.4), February 21, 1967
      (vol.31 no.5), March 7, 1967
      (vol.31 no.21), October 17, 1967
      (vol.31 no.13), June 25, 1968
    - Los Angeles Free Press. Los Angeles., 2 items: (Box 70)
      (Issue 175, vol.4 no.47), November 24-December 1, 1967
      (Issue 179, vol.4 no.51), December 22-28, 1967
    - Minority of One. Passaic, New Jersey., (8 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.8 no.3), March 1966
      (vol.8 no.7-8), July-August 1966
      (vol.8 no.9), September 1966
      (vol.8 no.10), October 1966
      (vol.8 no.11), November 1966
      (vol.8 no.12), December 1966
      (vol.9 no.12), December 1967
      (vol.10 no.9), September 1968
    - The Nation. New York., 4 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.202 no.24), June 13, 1966
      (vol.202 no.25), June 20, 1966
      (vol.203 no.2), July 11, 1966
      (vol.204 no.16), April 17, 1967
    - National Guardian. New York., 1 item: (Box 71)
      undated Special issue
    - New York Review of Books. New York., 2 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.7 no.1), July 28, 1966
      (vol.9 no.4), September 14, 1967
    - Paris Match. Paris., 1 item: (Box 71)
      (no.920), November 26, 1966
    - Playboy. Chicago., 2 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.14 no.2), February 1967
      (vol.14 no.10), October 1967
    - Ramparts. San Francisco., 2 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.5 no.7), January 1967
      (vol.6 no.6), January 1968
    - The Realist. New York., 1 item: (Box 71)
      (no.69), September 1966
    - Saturday Evening Post. Philadelphia., 3 items: (Box 71)
      (vol.240 no.1), January 14, 1967
      (vol.240 no.5), March 11, 1967
      (vol.240 no.24), December 2, 1967
    - Saturday Review. New York., 1 item: (Box 71)
      January 21, 1967
    - Time. New York., 1 item: (Box 71)
      (vol.88 no.12), September 16, 1966
    - West. Los Angeles., 2 items: (Box 71)
      November 27, 1966
      December 4, 1966
  - Clippings., (16 items) (Box 71)
- Guy Endore's Participation for the Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee
  - Clippings., (2 items) (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Aid to Sleepy Lagoon boys: Mexican Consul lauds 'Good Neighbor' work, 1944 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      Mexican Consul General Vicente Peralta lauds Carey McWilliams and the Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee for their work on behalf of the Sleepy Lagoon defendants.
    - Defense praised: General Cardenas hails Sleepy Lagoon Committee, 1944 August 24 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      Cárdenas, Secretary of National Defense and former president of Mexico, praises the work of the Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee.
      Name of newspaper not indicated.
  - Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee., (2 items) (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Endore's note., (1p., holograph) (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Membership list., (5pp., typescript carbon) (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - re dismissal of the case. By Guy Endore(?). Los Angeles., 1944; (4pp., typescript carbon) (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Endore, Guy. “Sleepy Lagoon boys are pronounced innocent.” Los Angeles., 1944; (5pp., typescript with holograph corrections) (Box 83, Folder 6)
    Draft for Endore's pamphlet, Sleepy Lagoon... Victory For Democracy (Los Angeles: Sleepy Lagoon Defense Committee, 1944). Utilizing extensive quotes from Alice McGrath's letter of October 25, 1944. This was expanded, revised, and quotations were deleted from the published version.
    - Sleepy Lagoon boys are pronounced innocent (draft), 1944 October (Box 83, Folder 6)
      Endore writes of the successful appeal of the convictions in the Sleepy Lagoon trial. He particularly points out the findings of Appellate Court Judge Thomas P. White that Judge Fricke, the Sleepy Lagoon trial presiding judge, had denied the defendants a fair trial through his rulings.
  - Isserman, Abraham J., (3 items) (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Letter to Guy Endore., April 26, 1944; (1 item) (Box 83, Folder 7)